

Languages

English - Advanced Spanish - Native

Skills

Hard



Soft

Communication	Teamwork	Social Skills
Taking Criticism	Proactivity	Creativity
Collaboration	Organization	Problem Solving

Education

- React: The complete guide @Udemy
- Google Analytics & SEO @GeekBoss
- Git & Github @Platzi
- User Experience & User Interface Design @Platzi
- Web Development @Platzi
- Multimedia Production Technology @SENA

▼ Social





About Me

I'm a passionate, proactive, with keen eye for details, **Product Developer** with 8 years of experience. My pasion is to build and maintain Design Systems in NextJS / ReactJS and Storybook, working together with design and frontend teams.

In my free time I like to study 📽 and play videogames 🧖.

Relevant Experience



Product Developer / Web Designer @Freelance January 2013 - Today

I help companies and startups to develop and maintain websites and design systems and their components in ReactJS and Storybook. Normally help to build the application layouts as well to make it responsive, and improve UX from UI development. In some cases I also do design job to help my clients build the entire product.



SSR UX Developer @MakingSense

January 2021 - Today

Working 100% remotely with an Argentinian and USA team on a huge app for agricultural sector. Some of my duties are to maintain an entire Design System built with ReactJS and Storybook, add new components based on designs, refactor old code moving from JS classes to hooks and Typescript, SASS to Styled Components and improve responsive.



UI Developer @10Pearls September 2019 - December 2020

I built the entire UI in ReactJS for an educational public project. I had to keep constant communication with the designers and product managers from USA to deliver the best product possible. I also communicated with the frontend team to deliver easy to use, scalable and maintainable components. Improved the UX adding extra UI functionalities, like Skeleton loading.



UI Developer @Integ.ro July 2018 - September 2019

I was, from start to end, building an entire website for a prestigious university from my city. The customer send us the designs and I turn them to life coding it on WordPress. One of the biggest challenges was to make it fully accesible so I had to research a lot and learn about ally implementation, testing and debugging.

Portfolio







Recommendations



Emily Biondo @10Pearls UX UI Design Lead

Alejandro is amazing at his job. He has an intuitive sensibility for UX and UI, and is a fantastic collaborator. Working with him was effortless—he was always responsive, always confident we could arrive at a solution, and always came through with effective, beautiful interfaces. I wish I could work with a thousand Alejandros.



Dylan Donlon-Moyer @10Pearls

Product Delivery Manager

Alejandro is an incredible UI/UX talent and an absolutely wonderful colleague to work with. He is responsive, friendly, and efficient in his duties, and is always eager to continue learning and improving the products he creates. He faithfully brings even the most complex designs to life and can always be counted on to build reliable and beautiful frameworks for any project. I would love to have Alejandro on all of my teams!



Liliana Franco @Integ.ro Scrum Master

Are you looking for a good team player? Then Alejo is definitely the right match. He is a great UI designer with a keen eye for details. He is always ready to help the team, ready to learn new things and ready for challenges. I worked with him for about one year and I would definitely repeat the experience.

Not convinced yet? Let's talk *>